<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psykiatri on Loggen</title>
    <link>/tags/psykiatri/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psykiatri on Loggen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/psykiatri/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Poddar om psykologi, psykiatri och kognition</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-17-podcasts-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-17-podcasts-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Hidden brain Hidden Brain’s host Shankar Vedantam reveals the unconscious patterns that drive human behavior, the biases that shape our choices, and the triggers that direct the course of our relationships.
Länk: https://www.npr.org/podcasts/510308/hidden-brain
Rekommenderade episoder: I’m Right, You’re Wrong, Radio Replay: Loving the Lie . Radio Replay: Crime As A Disease.
 Oxford psychiatry podcast These podcasts provide an introduction to core topics in psychiatry, and to research undertaken in the Oxford University Department of Psychiatry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vansinnet i historia och litteratur</title>
      <link>/post/madness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/madness/</guid>
      <description>Övrigt Dan Carlins podcast om religiöst vansinne i den Tyska staden Mûnster under 1500-talet:
 Murderous milennial preachers and prophets take over the German city of Munster after Martin Luther unleashes a Pandora’s Box of religious anarchy with the Protestant Revolution.
 Länk: Prophets of Doom
Distanskursen “Narrating madness” vid Umeå Universitet:
 While locating texts within their contemporary contexts as far as religion, gender and medicine, the course will engage with significant modern theoretical discussions of madness and creativity as offered by Foucault, Freud and others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dunedin Study</title>
      <link>/post/2018feb-dunedinstudy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018feb-dunedinstudy/</guid>
      <description>I “The Dunedin Multidisciplinary Health &amp;amp; Development Study” har man följt 1037 personer födda 1972-73 i över 40 år. Livshistoriens betydelse för åldrande, kognition med mera har studerats. Verkar intressant för att värdera effekter av arv och miljö.
The Dunedin Study
Om studien i ett podcastavsnitt från Science:
 Following 1000 people for decades to learn about the interplay of health, environment, and temperament  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>